ikmultimedia.com 2019-10-06

# IK Multimedia. Musicians First

We’d like to inform you about how your personal data is handled by IK Multimedia Production Srl, pursuant to Art.13 of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), (EU) 2016/679. 

**Data controller:** IK Multimedia Production Srl with registered office in via dell'Industria 46, 41122 Modena, Italy, Fiscal code/VAT: IT02359550361, Tel + 39 059/285496

**Contacts:** For any questions related to this Privacy Policy or to the processing of personal data carried out by IK Multimedia Production Srl, the user can: 

  * send an email request to: [privacy.ik@ikmultimedia.com](mailto:privacy.ik@ikmultimedia.com)
  * visit [www.ikmultimedia.com/contact-us-privacy](https://www.ikmultimedia.com/contact-us/ContactIKForm.php?R=privacy)

**General principles applicable to the processing of personal data:** The personal data you provide or obtain in interaction with us will be processed according to the principles of: 

  * lawfulness, correctness and transparency;
  * limitation of purpose;
  * data minimization;
  * accuracy of the data;
  * limitation of retention
  * integrity and confidentiality.

**Data source:** The data processed is obtained via direct registration by the user through the channels made available by IK Multimedia Production Srl, such as websites and applications. 

#### PURPOSE OF DATA HANDLING

**1\. CUSTOMER MANAGEMENT**  

Personal data or other elements of personal identification are processed in order to manage: 

  * Mandatory obligations by law in the fiscal and accounting fields
  * Payment transaction management
  * Management of contracts
  * Customer billing history

**Types of data collected:** Name, e-mail address, physical address (if provided), telephone or fax number (if provided), tax code (if provided), VAT number (if provided), IP address, in case of geolocation, and language. 

**Legal basis:** Execution of the contract. The processing of data by IK Multimedia Production Srl is necessary for the fulfillment of a contract of which you are a part. Legal obligation. The processing of data is necessary in order to comply with legal obligations, such as for tax purposes. 

**Data retention:** The data processed will be stored for a period of time not exceeding the completion of the purposes for which it is collected and processed and for the execution and fulfillment of contractual purposes; in case of handling due to legal obligations, the data will be stored as required by articles 2948 and 2220 of the civil code, art. 22 of the D.P.R. 29/09/1973 n.600. 

**2\. TECHNICAL SUPPORT**

With regard to technical support activities, your personal data will be processed in order to manage your requests sent via a specific form. 

**Types of data collected:** Name and surname, e-mail (required); telephone number (optional) 

**Legal basis:** Contractual. The processing of data by IK Multimedia Production Srl is necessary for the fulfillment of a contract of which you are a part. 

**Data transfer outside the European Union:** For the aforementioned purpose, personal data may be transferred to the company IK Multimedia US, LLC, with registered office in 590 Sawgrass Corporate Pkwy. - Sunrise, FL 33325 - Telephone: (954) 846-9101 - Fax: (954) 846-9077. The transfer is authorized on the basis of standard contractual clauses between IK Multimedia Production Srl and IK Multimedia US, LLC. 

**Data retention:** The data processed will be stored for a period of time not exceeding the completion of the purposes for which it is collected and processed and for the execution and fulfillment of contractual purposes; 

**3\. CONTACT FORM**

Your personal data will be processed in order to manage requests for general information, quotes, etc, sent via a specific form. 

**Types of data collected:** Name, surname, e-mail address and sector of activity. 

**Legal basis:** Pre-contractual execution. In the event that the processing of data by IK Multimedia Production Srl is necessary for the fulfillment of a contract of which the user is a party. 

**Data retention:** The data processed will be stored for a period of time not exceeding the completion of the purposes for which it is collected and processed and for the execution and fulfillment of contractual purposes; 

**4\. NEWSLETTER**  

After registering for the newsletter, your data will be processed in order to send e-mail messages containing commercial and promotional information relating to IK Multimedia Production Srl products. 

**Types of data collected:** E-mail address, location, product preferences 

**Legal basis:** Consent. The provision of data is optional with regard to the aforementioned purposes and any refusal to process data does not compromise the continuation of the contractual relationship. 

**Data retention:** The processed data will be stored in compliance with the terms prescribed by law for the type of activity or until the revocation of consent or exercise of the right to object as provided for by art. 21 EU Reg. 2016/679 

**5\. PROMOTIONAL ACTIVITIES AND STATISTICS**

While browsing, your personal data will be processed for the following purposes: 

  * Propose relevant and non-repetitive advertisement to users (including banners)
  * Determine interest in the products or services provided by IK Multimedia Production Srl

**Types of data collected:** e-mail address, navigation data 

**Legal basis:** Consent. The provision of data is optional with regard to the aforementioned purposes, and any refusal to process does not compromise the continuation of the contractual relationship. 

**Data retention:** The processed data will be stored in compliance with the terms prescribed by law for the type of activity or until the revocation of consent or exercise of the right to object as provided for by art. 21 EU Reg. 2016/679 

**Deactivation of cookies:** The user can change the settings to be informed when a cookie is set or updated, or to block cookies altogether through the browser settings. For more information, please refer to the user instructions of your browser. Please note that by blocking, disabling, or managing all cookies or some of them, you may not have access to certain features or offers on the websites or applications of IK Multimedia Production Srl. 

#### USER DATA LOCATION AND HANDLING

  * European Economic Area.
  * United States of America: the transfer is authorized on the basis of standard contractual clauses between IK Multimedia Production Srl and IK Multimedia US, LLC.
  * Canada: the transfer is authorized on the basis of the European Comminion decision from December 20, 2001.

#### DATA TRANSMISSION TO THIRD PARTIES

IK Multimedia Production Srl may transmit the user's personal data to third parties to the extent required by law, by court order or decisions made by legitimate public authorities and for law enforcement purposes. Your personal data may also be shared with the following third parties: 

  1. Consultants and independent contractors, either individually or in groups, financial intermediaries other than banks, such as PayPal and forwarding agents (for example, companies operating in the field of logistics). Such third-party providers have access to data to provide these services but cannot use your personal data for other purposes.
  2. IK Multimedia US, LLC, a company with registered office in the USA and a member of the Privacy Shield, for the provision of technical support to customers.
  3. Fender Musical Instruments Corporation, subject to user consent and limited to products developed under Fender license, for marketing purposes.
  4. Third parties to define, exercise or defend the legal rights of IK Multimedia Production Srl.
  5. Third parties in the event of any merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other arrangement of all activities or actions of IK Multimedia Production Srl or part of them (including, without limitation, bankruptcy or similar procedures). 

IK Multimedia Production Srl takes all reasonable measures to ensure that such third parties are bound by the obligations of privacy and protection of personal data. The transmission is carried out in compliance with the regulatory obligations, including the stipulation of agreements relating to the processing of data with third parties, the guarantee that personal data is processed according to our instructions, the law and regulations in force and for the purposes specified by IK Multimedia Production Srl as well as to guarantee adequate security measures. 

#### RIGHTS OF THE INTERESTED PARTY

You can exercise the rights provided by the Regulation articles 15 - 22) listed below: 

  * right of access to personal data;
  * right of rectification;
  * cancellation right (or right to be forgotten);
  * right to limit the processing of data;
  * the right to obtain notification in case of rectification or cancellation of personal data or
limitation of processing by the Data Controller; 
  * data portability right;
  * right to object to the processing;
  * the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling

Furthermore, you have the right to file a complaint with the Supervisory Authority if you believe that the treatment that concerns you violates the GDPR. Pursuant to art. 77 of the GDPR, the claim may be brought to the attention of a Supervisory Authority, in particular in the Member State in which you normally reside, work or to the Authority of the place where the alleged violation has occurred. You also have the right to mandate an organization or association active in the field of data protection that represents you and to file a complaint on your behalf. 

If the processing is based on consent, you have the right to revoke it at any time. The withdrawal of consent does not affect the lawfulness of the processing of data before the revocation. The right of revocation can be exercised by writing to: privacy.ik@ikmultimedia.com. 

#### DATA SECURITY

IK Multimedia Production Srl is committed to protecting the security of your personal data by adopting the necessary organizational, technical and administrative measures: Access control, transmission, input and availability, in addition to data separation.   
Anticipating access restrictions based on user name and password. It is important that the user always chooses a password that is difficult to identify.   
Information on the number of credit cards is addressed to one or more certified and approved service providers and will not be stored by IK Multimedia Production Srl. All external transmissions of personal data are protected by encryption. 

Some partial credit card information will remain encrypted on IK Multimedia Production servers to manage payments and prevent fraud. 

#### MINORS

Before accessing or providing personal data, users must state that they have reached the age of majority. Minors must obtain the prior consent of those who have parental responsibility. 

#### USE OF THIRD-PARTY SERVICES

The user, while browsing the site or using the IK Multimedia applications, may use services provided by third parties such as: 

  * AddThis: to facilitate the sharing of content on social networks
  * SoundCloud Widget: for the use of audio content
  * YouTube widget: for the use of video content
  * Dropbox, One Drive and Google Drive: to save and share created content
  * Facebook Custom Audience Pixel: to record information concerning the way in which visitors use our website and provides Facebook with information concerning the browser setting of the user, a hashed version of the Facebook ID and the URL which is being visited. Each Facebook user thus possesses a clear and device-independent Facebook ID, whereby it is possible to address the user via more than one device on the social network Facebook, recognise him and target advertising om the way Facebook adverts. After 180 days, the user information is deleted until the visitor accesses our website again. Therefore, no personal information is disclosed to us in relation to the individual website visitors. We can only solicit website customer target groups once the target customer group has reached a critical mass in terms of numbers. More information can be found in the Data Policy and the Terms of Service of Facebook Inc. You can deactivate the retargeting function via [your Facebook account](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen). 

#### CHANGES AND UPDATES TO THE PRIVACY INFORMATION

IK Multimedia Production Srl may modify or update this information as needed, to reflect changes in products and services, changes in applicable legislation, regulations or practices and to process customer feedback. We therefore invite users to periodically review this Privacy Policy. The date of the last update is always shown at the bottom of this document.   
In the event that substantial changes are made to this Privacy Policy, IK Multimedia Production Srl will inform you by posting or sending a notice. 

Last modification: **September 20, 2019**
